<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview Prep on Wahab Ahmad</title>
    <link>https://w28ahmad.github.io/categories/interview-prep/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview Prep on Wahab Ahmad</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 18:01:22 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://w28ahmad.github.io/categories/interview-prep/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Binary Trees</title>
      <link>https://w28ahmad.github.io/post/mastering_binary_trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 18:01:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://w28ahmad.github.io/post/mastering_binary_trees/</guid>
      <description>Overview Binary trees are a data strcture in computer science that consist of nodes with each node having at most $2$ children, referred to as left / right child. They are often used to organize data hierarchically, allowing efficient insertion, deletion and search operations. Common types of binary trees include binary search trees, where nodes are ordered such that for each node, all elements in its left subtree are less than the node&amp;rsquo;s value, and all nodes in its right subtree are greater than or equal to the node&amp;rsquo;s value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mastering Dynamic Programming</title>
      <link>https://w28ahmad.github.io/post/mastering_dynamic_programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 02:01:05 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://w28ahmad.github.io/post/mastering_dynamic_programming/</guid>
      <description>Overview Dynamic Programming is a general technique for solving optimization, search, and counting problems that can be decomposed to subproblems. In such problems, these subproblems commonly reoccur and so we must cache the solutions to the subproblems and use them to solve larger problems until we obtain the solution to the original problem.
Introduction Fibonacci Numbers Let us start with a rather simple example, Fibonacci Numbers are computed using the following formula $F(n) = F(n-1) + F(n-2)$ and constructs the following infinite sequence $0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, &amp;hellip;$ Since the new element in the sequence is generated using the previous 2 elements suggests that Dynamic Programming can be leveraged.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Patterns</title>
      <link>https://w28ahmad.github.io/post/design-patterns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 07:15:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://w28ahmad.github.io/post/design-patterns/</guid>
      <description>Overview Object-oriented design patterns are fundamental to programming. They are reusable solutions to common problems encountered during programming, often making heavy use of interfaces, information hiding, polymorphism, and intermediary objects. There are three main categories of design patterns that will be discussed in this blog:
Creational Patterns Structural Patterns Behavioral Patterns Other engineers have faced issues while developing applications, and they have come up with specific design patterns. We can leverage their knowledge in our own software design to simplify the process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
